Guide to the World War II posters and newsmaps collection, MS2254
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
World War II posters and newsmaps
Circa 1940-1945
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2254
11 Linear Feet
This collection contains posters and newsmaps related to World War II.
Restrictions on Access
This collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The donor of Series 1 is unknown. Series 2 donated by Michael Beaghen 2019 July 8 (Accession 2019.044)
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains posters and newsmaps related to World War II. The posters are arranged by size and alphabetically within a size range. The posters in Box 3 are all Navy recruiting posters. These appear to have been purchased by Dr. Elmer L. Kayser in his capacity of the University Historian.
Collection Organization
Organized into two series: Posters and Newsmaps for the Armed Forces
World War, 1939-1945; Political posters
- Posters, Circa 1938-1945; Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains posters related to World War II.
  Arrangement
  Arranged loosely by size.
  - A Message to Our Tenants from the U.S. Government (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Absence makes the war last longer, Your production committee says: Stay on the Job! (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cut Logs Now! Prices are up (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Don't be a dope! Handle Equipment Right (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Farm Scrap Builds Destroyers (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Farm Scrap Builds Tanks & Guns [2/2] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Give 'em Both Barrels (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - He Eats a Ton a Year, Your Farm Can Help (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hit 'em with Copper, Zinc, Lead (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Homemaker's War Guide (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - How to get farm help (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Instructions to a Saboteur (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Join the U.S. Truck Conservation Corps (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Leave the Flame-Throwing to US-You Be Careful with Fire! (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Spanish-language: Lutamos Pela Liberdade de Todos (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - More Copper-Zinc-Lead-quick! (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Our Freedoms and Rights (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pipedown Soldier! Tokio's Listening! (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Rationing Safeguards Your Share [2/2] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ships for Victory (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Somebody Blabbed, Button Your Lip! (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - This man is your friend--Chinese (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - This man is your friend--Englishman (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - This man is your friend--Ethiopian (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - This man is your friend--Russian (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - To all who use libraries (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - U.S. Needs Us Strong, Eat Nutritional Food (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - United States Controlled Prices (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Unlock the Door...Quick! (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Wanted for Victory (Box 1, Folder 30)
    General note
    Please note: this map is folded and curently can not be opened.
  - We are fighting the Axis, Not Each Other (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - We're in the Fight Too! (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Swedish-language: Amerikas Nyaste StÃrtbombare [2/2] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Buy War Bonds (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Buy War Bonds, Food-Guns-Planes-Tanks quick! (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Swedish-language: Den Slutliga Fredens Vapen (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Of the troops and for the troops, The Corps of Military Police (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Postal Telegraph (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Strong in the strength of the Lord... (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "This is a people's war ..." (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Swedish-language: Varldens Snabbaste Jaktplen (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1946 Resolution that every American buy and hold U.S. Savings Bonds (Oversize-folder 3, Item 1)
  - A careless word...another cross (Oversize-folder 4, Item 1)
  - Spanish-language: A Guerra Ilustrada (Oversize-folder 5, Item 1)
  - All These are Infantry (Oversize-folder 6, Item 1)
  - America Calling, Take your place in Civilian Defense (Oversize-folder 7, Item 1)
  - Americans! Share the meat as a wartime necessity [1/2] (Oversize-folder 8, Item 1)
  - Americans! Share the meat as a wartime necessity [2/2] (Oversize-folder 8, Item 2)
  - Books cannot be killed by fire (Oversize-folder 9, Item 1)
  - Brotherhood Week, February 19th to 28th, 1943 (Oversize-folder 10, Item 1)
  - Chinese-language: flags [1/5] (Oversize-folder 11, Item 1)
  - Chinese-language: flags 2 [2/5] (Oversize-folder 11, Item 2)
  - Chinese-language: plane [3/5] (Oversize-folder 11, Item 3)
  - Chinese-language: plane 2 [4/5] (Oversize-folder 11, Item 4)
  - Chinese-language: Statue of Liberty [5/5] (Oversize-folder 11, Item 5)
  - Clear the tracks for war shipments, Buy Coal Now! (Oversize-folder 12, Item 1)
  - Declaration by United Nations (Oversize-folder 13, Item 1)
  - Do with less--so they'll have enough! (Oversize-folder 14, Item 1)
  - "Doing all you can, brother?" Buy War Bonds (Oversize-folder 15, Item 1)
  - Executive Order 8802: Fair Employment in Defense Industries (Oversize-folder 16, Item 1)
  - Eyes of the Home Skies, Civil Air Patrol (Oversize-folder 17, Item 1)
  - Get a war job to help him fight (Oversize-folder 18, Item 1)
  - Get in the Scrap (Oversize-folder 19, Item 1)
  - Guard your family's health (Oversize-folder 20, Item 1)
  - Help Bring Them Back To You! Make Yours A Victory Home! (Oversize-folder 21, Item 1)
  - How to Fight Fire Bombs (Oversize-folder 22, Item 1)
  - I Need Your Skill in a War Job! (Oversize-folder 23, Item 1)
  - If you must talk tell it to the Marines (Oversize-folder 24, Item 1)
  - If you tell where they're going they may never get there! (Oversize-folder 25, Item 1)
  - I'll carry mine too! Trucks and tires must last till victory [1/2] (Oversize-folder 26, Item 1)
  - I'll carry mine too! Trucks and tires must last till victory [2/2] (Oversize-folder 26, Item 2)
  - Keep 'em Flying! (Oversize-folder 27, Item 1)
  - Keep Him Flying! Buy War Bonds (Oversize-folder 28, Item 1)
  - Keep Scrapping, America Needs More Rubber, Metals, Rags, Paper, Burlap (Oversize-folder 29, Item 1)
  - Our Good Earth ...Keep It Ours, Buy War Bonds (Oversize-folder 30, Item 1)
  - Ours... to fight for, Freedom from Fear (Oversize-folder 31, Item 1)
  - Plant a Victory Garden, Our Food is Fighting (Oversize-folder 32, Item 1)
  - Rationing means a fair share for all of us (Oversize-folder 33, Item 1)
  - Remember me? I was at Bataan, Buy War Bonds (Oversize-folder 34, Item 1)
  - Scrap (Oversize-folder 35, Item 1)
  - Show Your Timber! Cut Logs Now! (Oversize-folder 36, Item 1)
  - Take Care! Idle hands work for Hitler (Oversize-folder 37, Item 1)
  - The Atlantic Charter (Oversize-folder 38, Item 1)
  - The Present With a Future, War Bonds (Oversize-folder 39, Item 1)
  - The United Nations Fight for Freedom [1/2] (Oversize-folder 40, Item 1)
  - The United Nations Fight for Freedom [2/2] (Oversize-folder 40, Item 2)
  - They've got more important places to go than you!...Save Rubber (Oversize-folder 41, Item 1)
  - Universal Safety, U.S. Army Safety Program (Oversize-folder 42, Item 1)
  - War shipments mean less fuel for all (Oversize-folder 43, Item 1)
  - War Traffic Must Come First, Don't Waste Transportation (Oversize-folder 44, Item 1)
  - Warning, Sabotage (Oversize-folder 45, Item 1)
  - We Have Not a Minute to Lose (Oversize-folder 46, Item 1)
  - "We Shall Win or We Shall Die" (Oversize-folder 47, Item 1)
  - Where our men are fighting our food is fighting (Oversize-folder 48, Item 1)
  - Win With Tin (Oversize-folder 49, Item 1)
  - Your Country Expects You To:... (Oversize-folder 50, Item 1)
  - Your dimes did this for me! Join the March of Dimes (Oversize-folder 51, Item 1)
  - Your Red Cross must carry on! (Oversize-folder 52, Item 1)
  - A careless word ...another cross (Oversize-folder 53, Item 1)
  - America Calling, Take your place in Civilian Defense (Oversize-folder 54, Item 1)
  - Americans All (Oversize-folder 55, Item 1)
  - Attack Attack Attack, Buy War Bonds (Oversize-folder 57, Item 1)
  - Back 'Em Up with More Metal [1/2] (Oversize-folder 58, Item 1)
  - Back 'Em Up with More Metal [2/2] (Oversize-folder 58, Item 2)
  - Back 'Em Up with More Metal [1/2] (Oversize-folder 59, Item 1)
  - Back 'Em Up with More Metal [2/2] (Oversize-folder 59, Item 2)
  - Big Things From Little Ideas Grow, Speed Victory (Oversize-folder 60, Item 1)
  - Blast 'em out! Your Army needs more metal (Oversize-folder 61, Item 1)
  - "Bundles for Berlin," More Production (Oversize-folder 62, Item 1)
  - Defense Needs Rubber, Save Your Tires (Oversize-folder 63, Item 1)
  - Don't Let Him Down! (Oversize-folder 64, Item 1)
  - Don't Let That Shadow Touch Them, Buy War Bonds (Oversize-folder 65, Item 1)
  - Don't Throw Away Ammunition! [1/2] (Oversize-folder 66, Item 1)
  - Don't Throw Away Ammunition! [2/2] (Oversize-folder 66, Item 2)
  - Drive Slower in Hot Weather (Oversize-folder 67, Item 1)
  - Spanish-language: El Nuevo Orden-Del Eje (Oversize-folder 68, Item 1)
  - Every day you take off--gives the Axis a break (Oversize-folder 69, Item 1)
  - "Every man woman and child is a partner" [1/2] (Oversize-folder 70, Item 1)
  - "Every man woman and child is a partner" [2/2] (Oversize-folder 70, Item 2)
  - For their future- Buy War Bonds [1/2] (Oversize-folder 71, Item 1)
  - For their future- Buy War Bonds [2/2] (Oversize-folder 71, Item 2)
  - From mine to firing line, More Production (Oversize-folder 72, Item 1)
  - "Give 'em the stuff to fight with ..." (Oversize-folder 73, Item 1)
  - "Give 'em the stuff to fight with ..." Work for Freedom! (Oversize-folder 74, Item 1)
  - Good news from home, More Production [1/2] (Oversize-folder 75, Item 1)
  - Good news from home, More Production [2/2] (Oversize-folder 75, Item 2)
  - He's a fighting fool give him the best you've got, More Production [1/3] (Oversize-folder 76, Item 1)
  - He's a fighting fool give him the best you've got, More Production [2/3] (Oversize-folder 76, Item 2)
  - He's a fighting fool give him the best you've got, More Production [3/3] (Oversize-folder 76, Item 3)
  - How Mileage is Rationed (Oversize-folder 77, Item 1)
  - How to Shop with War Ration Book Two (Oversize-folder 78, Item 1)
  - Keep America Rolling! [1/2] (Oversize-folder 79, Item 1)
  - Keep America Rolling! [2/2] (Oversize-folder 79, Item 2)
  - Keep 'em Shooting! Your Army needs more metal [1/3] (Oversize-folder 80, Item 1)
  - Keep 'em Shooting! Your Army needs more metal [2/3] (Oversize-folder 80, Item 2)
  - Keep 'em Shooting! Your Army needs more metal [3/3] (Oversize-folder 80, Item 3)
  - Keep It Up Brother, This war's not won by a damn sight! (Oversize-folder 81, Item 1)
  - Keep the home fires burning, More Production (Oversize-folder 82, Item 1)
  - Kinda give it your personal attention, will you? (Oversize-folder 83, Item 1)
  - Let's give him enough and on time (Oversize-folder 84, Item 1)
  - Spanish-language: Libertad De Cultos (Oversize-folder 85, Item 1)
  - Spanish-language: Luchamos Pela Liberdade de Todos (Oversize-folder 86, Item 1)
  - Men Working Together! (Oversize-folder 87, Item 1)
  - More American workers were killed and wounded in Industrial accidents... (Oversize-folder 88, Item 1)
  - More Production--bomb (Oversize-folder 89, Item 1)
  - More Production--snowball (Oversize-folder 90, Item 1)
  - Official U.S. Defense Film Today (Oversize-folder 91, Item 1)
  - One day's power from Fontana Dam..., This is a war job (Oversize-folder 92, Item 1)
  - Out of Water Power Comes Air Power (Oversize-folder 93, Item 1)
  - Out of Water Power Comes Air Power ...These TVA Dams are needed for Victory (Oversize-folder 94, Item 1)
  - Pour It On! (Oversize-folder 95, Item 1)
  - Put your muscle on a war basis! More Production (Oversize-folder 96, Item 1)
  - Rationing means share and share alike (Oversize-folder 97, Item 1)
  - Save Rubber, Swap Rides [1/2] (Oversize-folder 98, Item 1)
  - Save Rubber, Swap Rides [2/2] (Oversize-folder 98, Item 2)
  - She's a swell plane--give us more! (Oversize-folder 99, Item 1)
  - "Thank God for American industry..." (Oversize-folder 100, Item 1)
  - The battle begins with your job! Do It Right [1/2] (Oversize-folder 101, Item 1)
  - The battle begins with your job! Do It Right [2/2] (Oversize-folder 101, Item 2)
  - The United Nations Fight for Freedom (Oversize-folder 102, Item 1)
  - They Stake Their Lives on Your Ordnance (Oversize-folder 103, Item 1)
  - They've got more important places to go than you!...Save Rubber (Oversize-folder 104, Item 1)
  - They've got the guts, give 'em more firepower (Oversize-folder 105, Item 1)
  - This is Your Firing Line! Stay on the Job (Oversize-folder 106, Item 1)
  - Together We Win, Get behind your labor-management committee (Oversize-folder 107, Item 1)
  - We Are Building This Dam (Oversize-folder 108, Item 1)
  - We French workers warn you ...defeat means slavery, starvation, death (Oversize-folder 109, Item 1)
  - "What you're making may save my daddy's life" (Oversize-folder 110, Item 1)
  - When You're A.W.O.L. You're Working for the Axis [1/2] (Oversize-folder 111, Item 1)
  - When You're A.W.O.L. You're Working for the Axis [2/2] (Oversize-folder 111, Item 2)
  - "You Bet I'm Going Back to Sea!" (Oversize-folder 112, Item 1)
  - You knock 'em out-We'll knock 'em down (Oversize-folder 113, Item 1)
  - Your scrap...brought it down (Oversize-folder 114, Item 1)
  - Give It Your Best! (Oversize-folder 115, Item 1)
  - Office of War Information presents Salvage (Oversize-folder 116, Item 1)
  - WEFT is a system for aircraft recognition (Oversize-folder 117, Item 1)
  - Liberty Bond posters [1/4] (Oversize-folder 118, Item 1)
  - Liberty Bond posters [2/4] (Oversize-folder 118, Item 2)
  - Liberty Bond posters [3/4] (Oversize-folder 118, Item 3)
  - Liberty Bond posters [4/4] (Oversize-folder 118, Item 4)
  - Will You Supply Eyes for the Navy?, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 1)
  - Sky Ships, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 2)
  - Wings, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 3)
  - Guardians of Freedom, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 4)
  - Serve With Pride and Patriotism, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 5)
  - I Want You for The Navy, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 6)
  - The Valiant Spirit of Our Navy, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 7)
  - What The Navy is Doing, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 8)
  - Peace on Earth Navy, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 9)
  - The Sea Inspires Great Deeds, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 10)
  - Join the Navy, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 11)
  - U.S. Naval Aviation, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 12)
  - Always Alert The Navy, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 13)
  - Gee I Wish I Were A Man I'd Join the Navy, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 14)
  - Young Men Wanted for U.S. Navy, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 15)
  - Follow The Flag, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 16)
  - Heritage Navy, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 17)
  - The Navy Needs You Don't Read American History Make It, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 18)
  - Enlist Now, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 19)
  - Yangtze River Gunboats, Circa 1940-1945 (Box 3, Item 20)
- Newsmaps for the Armed Forces, 1942-1945; Series 2
  The series contains one folder with 8 newsmaps for the armed forces.
  Vol. I No. 15 August 2, 1942 covering the week of July 24-31 Vol. I No. 20 September 7, 1942 covering the week August 28-September 4 Vol. III No. 26 F October 16, 1944 covering the week of October 4 -11 Vol. III No. 27 F October 23, 1944 covering the week of October 11 -18 Vol. III No. 28 F October 30, 1944 covering the week of October 18-25 Vol. III No. 38 F January 8, 1945 covering the week of December 27, 1944- January 3, 1945 Vol III No. 51 F April 19, 1945 covering the week of March 27 - April 3 Vol. IV No. 1 F April 23, 1945 covering the week of April 10-17
  Arranged in no particular order within the folder.
  - Newsmaps for the Armed Forces, 1942-1945; Series 2 (Oversize-folder 119)